The following content is provided
提供以下内容
under a Creative Commons license.
根据知识共享许可。
Your support will help MIT OpenCourseWare continue
您的支持将帮助MIT OpenCourseWare继续
to offer high quality educational resources for free.
免费提供高质量的教育资源。
To make a donation or view additional materials
捐款或查看其他材料
from hundreds of MIT courses, visit MIT OpenCourseWare
从数百门麻省理工学院的课程中，访问MIT OpenCourseWare
at ocw.mit.edu.
在ocw.mit.edu。
PROFESSOR: A trilogy, if you will, on hashing.
教授：如果您愿意的话，这是三部曲。
We did a lot of cool hashing stuff.
我们做了很多很棒的哈希操作。
In some sense, we already have what we want with hashing.
从某种意义上说，我们已经有了哈希所需的东西。
Hashing with chaining, we can do constant expected time,
通过链接进行哈希处理，我们可以执行固定的预期时间，
I should say, constant as long as-- yeah.
我应该说，只要保持不变，是的。
If we're doing insert, delete, and exact search.
如果我们要进行插入，删除和精确搜索。
Is this key in there?
里面有钥匙吗？
If so, return the item.
如果是这样，请退还该物品。
Otherwise, say no.
否则，拒绝。
And we do that with hashing with chaining.
我们通过链式哈希处理。
Under the analysis we did was with simple uniform hashing.
根据分析，我们所做的只是简单的统一哈希。
An alternative is to use universal hashing, which
一种替代方法是使用通用哈希，
is not really in this class.
不在这个班上。
But if you find this weird, then this is less weird.
但是，如果您发现这很奇怪，那么它就不会那么奇怪了。
And hashing with chaining, the idea
并通过链接进行哈希处理
was we had this giant universe of all keys, could be actually
是我们拥有所有按键的巨大宇宙，实际上
all integers.
所有整数。
So it's infinite.
所以它是无限的。
But then what we actually are storing in our structure
但是然后我们实际上存储在我们的结构中
is some finite set of n keys.
是n个键的某个有限集合。
Here, I'm labeling them k1 through k4, n is four.
在这里，我将它们标记为k1到k4，n为4。
But in general, you don't know what they're going to be.
但是总的来说，您不知道它们将是什么。
We reduce that to a table of size m
我们将其缩小为大小为m的表
by this hash function h-- stuff drawn in red.
通过此哈希函数h--用红色绘制的东西。
And so here I have a three way collision.
所以在这里我发生了三向碰撞。
These three keys all map to one, and so I
这三个键都映射为一个，所以我
store a linked list of k1, k4 and k2.
存储k1，k4和k2的链接列表。
They're in no particular order.
它们没有特定的顺序。
That's the point of that picture.
那就是那张照片的重点。
Here k3 happens to map to its own slot.
这里k3恰好映射到其自己的插槽。
And the other slots are empty, so they just
其他插槽是空的，所以它们只是
have a null saying there's an empty linked list there.
空值表示那里有一个空的链表。
Total size of this structure is n plus m.
此结构的总大小为n加m。
There's m to store the table.
这里有米来存放桌子。
There's n to store the sum of the lengths of all the lists
有n个存储所有列表的长度之和
is going to be n.
将是n。
And then we said the expected chain length,
然后我们说预期的链长，
if everything's uniform, then the probability
如果一切都统一，那么概率
of a particular key going to a particular slot is 1/m.
进入特定插槽的特定密钥的数量为1 / m。
And if everything's nice and independent
如果一切都很好并且独立
or if you use universal hashing, you
或者，如果您使用通用哈希，
can show that the total expected chain length is n/m.
可以表明预期的总链长为n / m。
n independent trials, each probability 1/m
n次独立试验，每项概率1 / m
of falling here.
落在这里。
And we call that alpha, the load factor.
我们称其为负荷系数。
And we concluded that the operation time
我们得出结论，手术时间
to do an insert, delete, or search was order 1 plus alpha.
要进行插入，删除或搜索的顺序是1加上alpha。
So that's n expectation.
所以这不是期望。
So that was hashing with chaining.
因此，这是通过链接进行哈希处理。
This is good news.
这是个好消息。
As long as alpha is a constant, we get constant time.
只要alpha是常数，我们就可以获得常数时间。
And just for recollection, today we're
只是为了回忆，今天我们
not really going to be thinking too much about what the hash
真的不会考虑太多的哈希
function is, but just remember two of them I talked
功能是，但只要记住我刚才说的两个
about-- this one we actually will use today, where you just
关于-我们实际上将在今天使用的那个
take the key and take it module m.
拿钥匙，把它拿到模块m中。
That's one easy way of mapping all integers into the space
这是将所有整数映射到空间的一种简单方法
zero through m minus 1.
零到m减1。
That's called the division method.
这就是所谓的除法。
Multiplication method is more fancy.
乘法方法更花哨。
You multiply by a random integer,
您乘以一个随机整数，
and then you look at the middle of that multiplication.
然后看一下乘法的中间部分。
And that's where lots of copies of the key k
那就是密钥k的很多副本
get mixed up together and that's sort of the name of hashing.
混合在一起，这就是哈希的名称。
And that's a better hash function in the real world.
这是现实世界中更好的哈希函数。
So that's hashing with chaining.
因此，这就是使用链式哈希。
Cool?
凉？
Now, it seemed like a complete picture,
现在，看起来像是一幅完整的图画，
but there's one crucial thing that we're missing here.
但是这里缺少一件关键的事情。
Any suggestions?
有什么建议么？
If I went to go to implement this data structure,
如果我去实现这个数据结构，
what don't I know how to do?
我不知道该怎么办？
And one answer could be the hash function,
一个答案可能是哈希函数，
but we're going to ignore that.
但我们将忽略这一点。
I know you know the answer.
我知道你知道答案。
Does anyone else know the answer?
还有其他人知道答案吗？
Yeah.
是的
AUDIENCE: Grow the table.
听众：长桌。
PROFESSOR: Grow the table.
教授：摆桌子。
Yeah.
是的
The question is, what should m be?
问题是，我应该是什么？
OK, we have to create a table size m,
好，我们必须创建一个大小为m的表格，
and we put our keys into it.
然后把钥匙放进去
We know we'd like m to be about the same as n.
我们知道我们希望m与n大致相同。
But the trouble is we don't really
但是麻烦是我们不是真的
know n because insertions come along,
知道n是因为插入
and then we might have to grow the table.
然后我们可能不得不扩大桌子。
If n gets really big relative to m,
如果n相对于m变得很大，
we're in trouble because this factor will go up
我们有麻烦，因为这个因素会上升
and it will be no longer constant time.
它将不再是固定的时间。
The other hand, if we set m to be really big,
另一方面，如果我们将m设置为很大，
we're also kind of wasteful.
我们也很浪费。
The whole point of this structure
这个结构的重点
was to avoid having one slot for every possible key
是为了避免每个可能的钥匙都有一个插槽
because that was giant.
因为那是巨大的。
We want it to save space.
我们希望它节省空间。
So we want m to be big enough that our structure is fast,
所以我们希望m足够大以使我们的结构快速，
but small enough that it's not wasteful in space.
但足够小，不会浪费空间。
And so that's the remaining question.
这就是剩下的问题。
We want m to be theta n.
我们希望m为theta n。
We want it to be omega n.
我们希望它是欧米茄n。
So we want it to be at least some constant times n,
所以我们希望它至少是常数n
in order to make alpha be a constant.
为了使alpha为常数。
And we want it to be big O of n in order
我们希望它成为n的大O
to make the space linear.
使空间线性化。
And the way we're going to do this, as we suggested,
就像我们建议的那样，
is to grow the table.
是为了长大桌子。
We're going to start with m equals some constant.
我们将从m等于某个常数开始。
Pick your favorite constant.
选择您喜欢的常数。
That's 20.
那是20
My favorite constant's 7.
我最喜欢的常数是7。
Probably want it to be a power of two, but what the hell?
可能希望它是2的幂，但是到底是什么？
And then we're going to grow and shrink as necessary.
然后，我们将根据需要进行增长和收缩。
This is a pretty obvious idea.
这是一个很明显的想法。
The interesting part is to get it to work.
有趣的部分是使其工作。
And it's going to introduce a whole new concept, which
它将引入一个全新的概念，
is amortization.
是摊销。
So it's going to be cool.
所以这将很酷。
Trust me.
相信我。
Not only are we going to solve this problem of how
我们不仅要解决这个问题，
to choose m, we're also going to figure out how the Python data
选择m，我们还将弄清楚Python数据如何
structure called list, also known as array, is implemented.
实现了称为列表的结构，也称为数组。
So it's the exactly the same problem.
因此，这是完全相同的问题。
I'll get to that in a moment.
一会儿，我会解决的。
So for example, let's say that we-- I said m
举例来说，我们说
should be theta n.
应该是theta n。
Let's say we want m to be at least n at all times.
假设我们一直希望m至少为n。
So what happens, we start with m equals 8.
那么发生了什么，我们从m等于8开始。
And so, let's say we start with an empty hash
因此，假设我们从一个空哈希开始
table, an empty dictionary.
表，一个空字典。
And then I insert eight things.
然后我插入八件事。
And then I go to insert the ninth thing.
然后我插入第九件事。
And I say, oh, now m is bigger than n.
我说，哦，现在m比n大。
What should I do?
我该怎么办？
So this would be like at the end of an insertion algorithm.
因此，这就像插入算法的末尾一样。
After I insert something and say oh, if m is greater than n,
我插入一些东西然后说哦，如果m大于n，
then I'm getting worried that m is getting much bigger than n.
那么我就担心m比n大很多。
So I'd like to grow the table.
所以我想扩大桌子。
OK?
好？
Let's take a little diversion to what does grow a table mean.
让我们稍微转移一下表的增长。
So maybe I have current size m and I'd
所以也许我现在的尺码是m
like to go to a new size, m prime.
喜欢去一个新的大小，素数。
This would actually work if you're growing or shrinking,
如果您正在增长或收缩，这实际上会起作用，
but m could be bigger or smaller than m prime.
但是m可以大于或小于m素数。
What should I do-- what do I need
我该怎么办-我需要什么
to do in order to build a new table of this size?
要做一个如此大的新表？
Easy warm up.
容易热身。
Yeah?
是啊
AUDIENCE: Allocate the memory and then rehash [INAUDIBLE].
听众：分配内存，然后重新哈希[听不清]。
PROFESSOR: Yeah.
教授：是的。
Allocate the memory and rehash.
分配内存并重新哈希。
So we have all these keys.
因此，我们拥有所有这些键。
They're stored with some hash function in here,
它们与哈希函数一起存储在这里，
in table size m.
在桌子上
I need to build an entirely new table,
我需要建立一个全新的表，
size m prime, and then I need to rehash everything.
大小为质数，然后我需要重新整理所有内容。
One way to think of this is for each item in the old table,
考虑这一点的一种方法是针对旧表中的每个项目，
insert into the new table, T prime.
插入新表T素数。
I think that's worth a cushion.
我认为这值得缓冲。
You got one?
你有一个？
You don't want to get hit.
你不想受到打击。
It's fine.
没关系。
We're not burning through these questions fast enough,
我们没有足够快地解决这些问题，
so answer more questions.
因此，请回答更多问题。
OK.
好。
So how much time does this take?
那么这需要多少时间？
That's the main point of this exercise.
这是本练习的重点。
Yeah?
是啊
AUDIENCE: Order n.
观众：订单n。
PROFESSOR: Order n.
教授：n阶。
Yeah, I think as long as m and m prime are theta n,
是的，我想只要m和m素数都是theta n，
this is order n.
这是命令n。
In general, it's going to be n plus m plus m prime,
通常，它将是n加m加m素数，
but you're right.
但是你是对的
Most of the time that's-- I mean,
在大多数情况下-我是说，
in the situation we're going to construct,
在我们要构建的情况下，
this will be theta n.
这将是theta n。
But in general, there's this issue that, for example,
但是总的来说，有一个问题，例如
to iterate over every item in the table you
遍历表中的每个项目
have to look at every slot.
必须查看每个插槽。
And so you have to pay order m just
所以你只需要支付订单
to visit every slot, order n to visit all those lists, m
访问每个广告位，命令n访问所有这些列表，m
prime just to build the new table, size m prime.
prime仅用于构建新表，大小为m prime。
Initialize it all to nil.
全部初始化为零。
Good.
好。
I guess another main point here is
我想这里的另一个重点是
that we have to build a new hash function.
我们必须构建一个新的哈希函数。
Why do we need to build a new hash function?
为什么我们需要构建一个新的哈希函数？
Because the hash function-- why did I call it f prime?
因为哈希函数-为什么将其称为f素数？
Calling it h prime.
称它为素数。
The hash function is all about mapping the universe of keys
哈希函数是关于映射键范围的全部
to a table of size m.
到尺寸为m的表。
So if m changes, we definitely need a new hash function.
因此，如果m发生变化，我们肯定需要一个新的哈希函数。
If you use the old hash function,
如果您使用旧的哈希函数，
you would just use the beginning of the table.
您只需要使用表格的开头即可。
If you add more slots down here, you're not going to use them.
如果您在此处添加更多插槽，则不会使用它们。
For every key you've got to rehash it,
对于您必须重新加密的每个密钥，
figure out where it goes.
弄清楚它的去向。
I think I've drilled that home enough times.
我想我已经在家里钻了足够的时间了。
So the question becomes when we see that our table is too big,
所以问题就出在我们看到我们的桌子太大时，
we need to make it bigger.
我们需要使其更大。
But how much bigger?
但是要大多少？
Suggestions?
有什么建议吗？
Yeah?
是啊
AUDIENCE: 2x.
听众：2倍。
PROFESSOR: 2x.
教授：2倍。
Twice m.
两次
Good suggestion.
好建议。
Any other suggestions?
还有其他建议吗？
3x?
3倍？
OK.
好。
m prime equals 2 m is the correct answer.
m素数等于2 m是正确答案。
But for fun, or for pain I guess,
但是我想是为了娱乐还是为了痛苦，
let's think about the wrong answer, which would be,
让我们考虑一个错误的答案，那就是，
just make it one bigger.
只是把它做大一点。
That'll make m equal to n again, so that
这将使m再次等于n，因此
seems-- it's at least safe.
似乎-至少是安全的。
It will maintain my invariant that m is at least n.
它将保持我的不变性，即m至少为n。
I get this wrong-- sorry, that's the wrong way.
我错了-抱歉，那是错误的方式。
n is greater than m.
n大于m。
I want m to be greater than or equal to n.
我希望m大于或等于n。
So if we just incremented our table size,
因此，如果我们只是增加表的大小，
then the question becomes, what is the cost of n insertions?
那么问题就变成了，n次插入的成本是多少？
So say we start with an empty table
所以说我们从一个空表开始
and it has size eight or whatever,
它有八号或其他尺寸，
some constant, and we insert n times.
一些常数，我们插入n次。
Then after eight insertions when we insert we
然后在插入八次之后，我们插入
have to rebuild our entire table.
必须重建我们的整个表。
That takes linear time.
这需要线性时间。
After we insert one more, we have to rebuild.
再插入一个之后，我们必须重建。
That takes linear time.
这需要线性时间。
And so the cost is going to be something like,
因此，成本将约为
after you get to 8, it's going to be 1 plus 2 plus 3 plus 4.
达到8后，它将是1加2加3加4。
So a triangular number.
所以是一个三角数。
Every time we insert, we have to rebuild everything.
每次插入时，我们都必须重建所有内容。
So this is quadratic, this is bad.
所以这是二次的，这很不好。
Fortunately, if all we do is double m, we're golden.
幸运的是，如果我们要做的只是double m，那么我们就很成功。
And this is sort of the point of why
这就是为什么
it's called table-- I call it table resizing there.
它称为表格-我称它为表格调整大小。
Or to not give it away, but this is
还是不放弃它，但这是
a technique called table doubling.
一种称为表加倍的技术。
And let's just think of the cost of n insertions.
让我们考虑一下n个插入的代价。
There's also deletions.
也有删除。
But if we just, again, start with an empty table,
但是，如果我们再次从一个空表开始，
and we repeatedly insert, then the cost
然后我们反复插入，然后
we get-- if we double each time and we're inserting,
我们得到-如果我们每次加倍并插入，
after we get to 8, we insert, we double to 16.
达到8后，我们插入，然后翻倍为16。
Then we insert eight more times, then we double to 32.
然后再插入八次，然后再翻倍至32。
Then we insert 16 times, then we double to 64.
然后我们插入16次，然后我们加倍到64。
All these numbers are roughly the same.
所有这些数字大致相同。
They're within a factor of two of each other.
它们彼此之间相差两个因子。
Every time we're rebuilding in linear time,
每次我们在线性时间内重建时，
but we're only doing it like log end times.
但我们只是像日志结束时间那样做。
If we're going from one to n, their log end growths--
如果我们从1转到n，则它们的对数结尾增长-
log end doublings that we're able to do.
记录我们能够做到的倍增。
So you might think, oh, it's n log n.
因此，您可能会想，哦，这是n log n。
But we don't want n log n.
但是我们不希望n log n。
That would be binary search trees.
那将是二进制搜索树。
We want to do better than n log n.
我们要比n log n做得更好。
If you think about the costs here,
如果您考虑一下这里的费用，
the cost to rebuild the first time is concepts, like 8.
第一次重建的成本是概念，例如8。
And then the cost to rebuild the second time
然后第二次重建的费用
is 16, so twice that.
是16，所以是原来的两倍。
The cost to build the next time is 64.
下次构建的成本为64。
So these go up geometrically.
所以这些几何地上升。
You've got to get from 1 to n with log end steps.
您必须从1到n加上日志结束步骤。
The natural way to do it is by doubling,
自然的方法是加倍，
and you can prove that indeed this is the case.
您可以证明确实是这种情况。
So this is a geometric series.
所以这是一个几何级数。
Didn't mean to cross it out there.
并不是要把它划掉。
And so this is theta n.
所以这就是theta n。
Now, it's a little strange to be talking about theta n.
现在，谈论theta n有点奇怪。
This is a data structure supposed
这是假设的数据结构
to be constant time per operation.
每次操作要保持恒定的时间。
This data structure is not constant time per operation.
该数据结构的每次操作时间不是恒定的。
Even ignoring all the hashing business,
即使不理会所有哈希运算，
all you're trying to do is grow a table.
您要做的就是增加一张桌子。
It takes more than constant time for some operations.
对于某些操作，它花费的时间超过了固定时间。
Near the end, you have to rebuild the last time,
快要结束了，您必须重新构建上一次，
you're restructuring the entire table.
您正在重组整个表。
That take linear time for one operation.
一个操作花费线性时间。
You might say that's bad.
您可能会说这很糟糕。
But the comforting thing is that there
但令人欣慰的是
are only a few operations, log end of them,
只是一些操作，记录它们的结尾，
that are really expensive.
那真的很贵。
The rest are all constant time.
其余的都是固定的时间。
You don't do anything.
你什么都不做。
You just add into the table.
您只需添加到表中即可。
So this is an idea we call amortization.
因此，这就是我们称为摊销的想法。
Maybe I should write here-- we call this table doubling.
也许我应该在这里写-我们将此表加倍。
So the idea with amortization, let me give you a definition.
因此，关于摊销的想法，让我给您一个定义。
Actually, I'm going to be a little bit vague here
其实我在这里有点模糊
and just say-- T of n.
只是说-T of n。
Let me see what it says in my notes.
让我看看笔记中的内容。
Yeah.
是的
I say T of n.
我说T等于n。
So we're going to use a concept of-- usually
因此，我们通常会使用-
we say running time is T of n.
我们说运行时间是n的T。
And we started saying the expected running time
我们开始说预期的运行时间
is some T of n plus alpha or whatever.
是n加上T或任何其他字母的T。
Now, we're going to be able to say the amortized running time
现在，我们可以说摊销的运行时间
is T of n, or the running time is T of n amortized.
是n的T，或者运行时间是n的T摊销。
That's what this is saying.
这就是这个意思。
And what that means is that it's not
那意味着不是
any statement about the individual running
关于个人跑步的任何陈述
time of the operations.
手术时间。
It's saying if you do a whole bunch of operations, k of them,
就是说，如果您进行一整堆操作，其中k个操作，
then the total running time is, at most, k times T of n.
那么总运行时间最多为n的k倍。
This is a way to amortize, or to-- yeah,
这是一种摊销方式，或者-
amortize-- this is in the economic sense of amortize,
摊销-从经济意义上讲是摊销，
I guess.
我猜。
You spread out the high costs so that's it's cheap on average
您摊开了高昂的成本，因此平均来说很便宜
all the time.
每时每刻。
It's kind of like-- normally, we pay rent every month.
有点像-通常，我们每个月支付租金。
But you could think of it instead as you're only
但是您可能会想到它，因为您只是
paying $50 a day or something for your monthly rent.
每天支付$ 50或您月租的费用。
It's maybe-- if you want to smooth things out,
也许-如果您想使事情顺利进行，
that would be a nice way to think about paying rent,
那是考虑支付租金的好方法，
or every second you're paying a penny or something.
或每秒钟您要支付一分钱或其他费用。
It's close, actually.
实际上，这很接近。
Little bit off, factor or two.
一点点关闭，因素或两个。
Anyway, so that's the idea.
无论如何，这就是想法。
So you can think of-- this is kind
所以您可以想到-这是一种
of like saying that the running time of an operation
就像说一个手术的运行时间
is T of n on average.
平均为n的T。
But put that in quotes.
但是用引号引起来。
We don't usually use that terminology.
我们通常不使用该术语。
Maybe put a Tilda here.
也许在这里放一个蒂尔达。
Where the average is taken over all the operations.
在所有操作中均取平均值。
So this is something that only makes
所以这只能使
sense for data structures.
数据结构的意义。
Data structures are things that have lots of operations on them
数据结构是对它们进行大量操作的事物
over time.
随着时间的推移。
And if you just-- instead of counting individual operation
如果您只是-而不是计算单个操作
times and then adding them up, if you add them up and then
时间，然后将它们加起来，如果您将它们加起来，然后
divide by the number of operations,
除以操作次数，
that's your amortized running time.
那就是您摊销的运行时间。
So the point is, in table doubling,
因此，在表加倍时，关键是
the amortized running time is beta 1.
摊销的运行时间为beta 1。
Because it's n in total-- at this point
因为总共是n
we've only analyzed insertions.
我们仅分析了插入。
We haven't talked about deletions.
我们还没有谈论删除。
So k inserts.
因此，k个插入。
If we're just doing insertions, take beta k time in total.
如果我们只是在做插入操作，则总共要花费beta k时间。
So this means constant amortized per insert.
因此，这意味着每次插入将摊销常数。
OK, it's a simple idea, but a useful one
好，这是一个简单的主意，但有用的一个主意
because typically-- unless you're in like a real time
因为通常-除非您实时
system-- you typically only care about the overall running
系统-您通常只关心整体运行情况
time of your algorithm, which might use a data
算法的时间（可能使用数据）
structure as a sub routine.
结构作为子例程。
You don't care if individual operations are
您不在乎单个操作是否
expensive as long as all the operations together are cheap.
只要所有操作加在一起都是便宜的就可以了。
You're using hashing to solve some other problem,
您正在使用哈希来解决其他一些问题，
like counting duplicate words in doc dist.
就像在doc dist中计算重复的单词一样。
You just care about the running time of counting duplicate
您只需要担心重复计数的运行时间
words.
话。
You don't care about how long each step of the for loop
您不必担心for循环的每个步骤要花多长时间
takes, just the aggregate.
需要，只是合计。
So this is good most of the time.
因此，这在大多数情况下都是很好的。
And we've proved it for insertions.
我们已经证明了它可以插入。
It's also true when you have deletions.
当您删除内容时也是如此。
You have k inserts and deletes.
您有k个插入和删除。
They certainly take order k time.
他们当然需要k时间。
Actually, this is easy to prove at this point
实际上，这点很容易证明
because we haven't changed delete.
因为我们没有更改删除。
So, what delete does is it just deletes something
因此，删除功能只是删除一些内容
from the table, leaves the table the same size.
从桌子上离开时，桌子的大小相同。
And so it actually makes life better for us
因此，这实际上使我们的生活更美好
because if it decreases m, in order to make m big again,
因为如果减小m为了再次增大m
you have to do more insertions than you had to before.
您必须比以前做更多的插入。
And the only extra cost we're thinking about here
而我们正在考虑的唯一额外费用
is the growing, the rebuild cost from inserting too big.
随着增长，插入的重建成本太大。
And so this is still true.
因此，这仍然是正确的。
Deletions only help us.
删除仅对我们有帮助。
If you have k total inserts and deletes, then still be order k.
如果您总共有k个插入和删除，则仍为k。
So still get constant amortized.
因此仍要不断摊销。
But this is not totally satisfying
但这并不完全令人满意
because of table might get big again.
因为桌子可能会再次变大。
m might become much larger than n.
m可能变得比n大得多。
For example, suppose I do n inserts
例如，假设我不插入
and then I do n deletes.
然后我不删除。
So now I have an empty table, n equals 0,
所以现在我有一个空表，n等于0，
but m is going to be around the original value of n,
但是m会在n的原始值附近，
or the maximum value of n over time.
或n随时间的最大值。
So we can fix that.
因此，我们可以解决该问题。
Suggestions on how to fix that?
有关如何解决该问题的建议？
This is a little more subtle.
这有点微妙。
There's two obvious answers.
有两个明显的答案。
One is correct and the other is incorrect.
一个是正​​确的，另一个是不正确的。
Yeah?
是啊
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE]
观众：[听不清]
PROFESSOR: Good.
教授：很好。
So option one is if the table becomes half the size,
所以选择之一是如果桌子的大小变成一半，
then shrink-- to half the size?
然后缩小-缩小一半？
Sure.
当然。
OK.
好。
That's on the right track.
那是正确的。
Anyone see a problem with that?
有人看到这个问题吗？
Yeah?
是啊
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE] when you're going from like 8 to 9,
观众：[听不清]当您从8点到9点时
you can go from 8 to 9, 9 to 8, [INAUDIBLE].
您可以从8到9、9到8 [听不清]。
PROFESSOR: Good.
教授：很好。
So if you're sizing and say you have eight items in your table,
因此，如果您要调整大小并说表中有八个项目，
you add a ninth item and so you double to 16.
您添加了第九项，因此加倍至16。
Then you delete that ninth item, you're back to eight.
然后删除第九项，回到八。
And then you say oh, now m equals n/2,
然后你说哦，现在m等于n / 2，
so I'm going to shrink to half the size.
所以我要缩小到一半的尺寸。
And if I insert again-- delete, insert, delete,
如果我再次插入-删除，插入，删除，
insert-- I spend linear time for every operation.
插入-我为每个操作花费线性时间。
So that's the problem.
这就是问题所在。
This is slow.
太慢了
If we go from 2 to the k to 2 to the k plus 1,
如果我们从2到k到2到k加1，
we go this way via-- oh sorry, 2 to the k plus 1.
我们通过-抱歉，2等于k加1。
Then, I said it right, insert to go to the right,
然后，我说对了，插入到右边，
delete to go to the left.
删除以转到左侧。
Then we'll get linear time for operation.
然后，我们将获得线性运行时间。
That is that.
就这样。
So, how do we fix this?
那么，我们该如何解决呢？
Yeah.
是的
AUDIENCE: Maybe m equal m/3 or something?
听众：也许m等于m / 3或其他？
PROFESSOR: M equals n over 3.
教授：M等于n大于3。
Yep.
是的
AUDIENCE: And then still leave it [INAUDIBLE].
听众：然后仍然将其[听不清]。
PROFESSOR: Good.
教授：很好。
I'm going to do 4, if you don't mind.
如果您不介意，我将做4。
I'll keep it powers of 2.
我将保持2的幂。
Any number bigger than 3 will work--
任何大于3的数字都可以工作-
or any number bigger than 2 will work here.
或任何大于2的数字都可以在这里使用。
But it's kind of nice to stick to powers of two.
但是坚持两个的幂是一种很好的选择。
Just for fun.
纯娱乐。
I mean, doesn't really matter because, as you say,
我的意思是，这并不重要，因为正如您所说，
we're still going to shrink to half the size,
我们仍然会缩小到一半，
but we're only going to trigger it when we are 3/4 empty.
但是我们只有在3/4空时才会触发它。
We're only using a quarter of the space.
我们只使用了四分之一的空间。
Then, it turns out you can afford
然后，事实证明你买得起
to shrink to half the size because in order
缩小到一半的尺寸，因为
to explode again, in order to need to grow again,
再次爆炸，为了再次成长，
you have to still insert n over m-- m over 2 items.
您仍必须在m到m之间插入n到2个项目。
Because it's half empty.
因为一半是空的。
So when you're only a quarter full,
所以当你只有四分之一的时间
you shrink to become a half full because then to grow again
你收缩到半饱，因为然后又长大
requires a lot of insertions.
需要很多插入。
I haven't proved anything here, but it turns out
我在这里还没有证明任何东西，但是事实证明
if you do this, the amortized time becomes constant.
如果执行此操作，则摊销时间将保持不变。
For k insertions and deletions, arbitrary combination,
对于k个插入和删除，任意组合，
you'll maintain linear size because of these two--
由于这两个原因，您将保持线性尺寸-
because you're maintaining the invariant
因为你要保持不变
that m is between n and 4n.
m在n和4n之间。
You maintain that invariant.
您保持不变。
That's easy to check.
很容易检查。
So you always have linear size.
因此，您始终具有线性大小。
And the amortized running time becomes constant.
并且摊销的运行时间变得恒定。
We don't really have time to prove that in the class.
我们真的没有时间在课堂上证明这一点。
It's a little bit tricky.
这有点棘手。
Read the textbook if you want to know it.
如果您想知道，请阅读教科书。
That's table doubling.
那是桌子的两倍。
Questions?
有什么问题吗
All right.
好吧。
Boring.
无聊
No.
没有。
It's cool because not only can we
很酷，因为我们不仅可以
solve the hashing problem of how do we set m in order
解决我们如何按顺序设置m的哈希问题
to keep alpha a constant, we can also solve Python lists.
为了保持alpha不变，我们还可以解析Python列表。
Python lists are also known as resizable arrays.
Python列表也称为可调整大小的数组。
You may have wondered how they work.
您可能想知道它们如何工作。
Because they offer random access,
由于它们提供随机访问权限，
we can go to the ith item in constant time
我们可以在固定时间内去第ith个项目
and modify it or get the value.
并对其进行修改或获取值。
We can add a new item at the end in constant time.
我们可以在固定时间结束时添加一个新项目。
That's append.
附上。
list.append.
list.append。
And we can delete the last item in constant time.
我们可以在固定时间内删除最后一个项目。
One version is list.pop.
一种版本是list.pop。
It's also delete list, square bracket minus 1.
它也是删除列表，方括号减1。
You should know that deleting the first item
您应该知道删除第一项
is not constant time.
不是固定的时间。
That takes linear time because what
这需要线性时间，因为
it does is it copies all the values over.
它确实将所有值复制过来。
Python lists are implemented by arrays.
Python列表由数组实现。
But how do you support this dynamicness
但是你如何支持这种动力
where you can increase the length and decrease the length,
您可以在其中增加长度并减少长度，
and still keep linear space?
并仍然保持线性空间？
Well, you do table doubling.
好吧，你做表加倍。
And I don't know whether Python uses
而且我不知道Python是否使用
two or some other constant, but any constant
两个或其他常数，但任何常数
will do, as long as the deletion constant is
只要删除常数是
smaller than the insertion constant.
小于插入常数。
And that's how they work.
这就是他们的工作方式。
So in fact, list.append and list.pop
所以实际上，list.append和list.pop
are constant amortized.
固定摊销。
Before, we just said for simplicity,
之前，我们只是为了简单起见，
they're constant time and for the most part
他们是恒定的时间，在大多数情况下
you can just think of them as constant time.
您可以将它们视为恒定时间。
But in reality, they are constant amortized.
但实际上，它们会不断摊销。
Now for fun, just in case you're curious,
现在好玩，以防万一您好奇
you can do all of this stuff in constant worst case
您可以在最坏的情况下完成所有这些工作
time per operation.
每次操作的时间。
May be a fun exercise.
可能是一个有趣的练习。
Do you want to know how?
你想知道吗？
Yeah?
是啊
Rough idea is when you realize that you're
粗略的想法是当你意识到自己是
getting kind of full, you start building on the side
变得有点饱，你开始在侧面建造
a new table of twice the size.
一个两倍大的新表。
And every time you insert into the actual table,
每次您插入实际表格时，
you move like five of the items over to the new table,
您将其中五个项目移到新表格中，
or some constant-- it needs to be a big enough constant.
或某个常数-它必须足够大。
So that by the time you're full, you just
这样，当您吃饱的时候，
switch over immediately to the other structure.
立即切换到其他结构。
It's kind of cool.
挺酷的
It's very tricky to actually get that to work.
实际操作起来非常棘手。
But if you're in a real time system,
但是如果您使用的是实时系统，
you might care to know that.
您可能会想知道这一点。
For the most part, people don't implement those things
在大多数情况下，人们不会执行那些事情
because they're complicated, but it
因为它们很复杂，但是
is possible to get rid of all these amortized.
有可能摆脱所有这些摊销。
Cool.
凉。
Let's move onto the next topic, which is more hashing related.
让我们进入下一个与散列相关的主题。
This was sort of general data structures
这是一般的数据结构
in order to implement hashing with chaining,
为了通过链接实现散列，
but didn't really care about hashing per se.
但并不真正在乎哈希本身。
We assumed here that we can evaluate the hash function
我们在这里假设我们可以评估哈希函数
in constant time, that we can do insertion in constant time,
在固定时间内，我们可以在固定时间内进行插入，
but that's the name of the game here.
但这就是这里的游戏名称。
But otherwise, we didn't really care--
但除此之外，我们并不在乎-
as long as the rebuilding was linear time,
只要重建是线性时间，
this technique works.
这种技术有效。
Now we're going to look at a new problem that
现在我们要看一个新的问题
has lots of practical applications.
有很多实际应用。
I mentioned some of these problems
我提到了其中一些问题
in the last class, which is string matching.
在最后一个类中，它是字符串匹配。
This is essentially the problem.
这本质上是问题。
How many people have used Grep in their life?
一生中有多少人使用过Grep？
OK, most of you.
好，你们大多数人
How many people have used Find in a text editor?
有多少人在文本编辑器中使用过查找？
OK, the rest of you.
好，其余的人
And so this are the same sorts of problems.
因此，这是同样的问题。
You want to search for a pattern, which is just
您想搜索一个模式，这仅仅是
going to be a substring in some giant string which
将会是一些巨大的弦中的一个子弦
is your document, your file, if you will.
是您的文档，还是文件（如果需要）。
So state this formally-- given two strings, s and t,
因此，用两个字符串s和t正式表述这一点，
you want to know does s occur as a substring of t?
您想知道s是否作为t的子串出现？
So for example, maybe s is a string 6006
例如，也许s是字符串6006
and t is your entire-- the mail that you've ever
这是您的全部-您曾经拥有的邮件
received in your life or your inbox, or something.
生活中或收件箱中收到的东西。
So t is big, typically, and s is small.
因此，t通常很大，而s很小。
It's what you type usually.
通常是您输入的内容。
Maybe you're searching for all email from Piazza,
也许您正在搜索来自Piazza的所有电子邮件，
so you put the Piazza from string or whatever.
因此，您可以从字符串或其他任何东西放置广场。
You're searching for that in this giant thing
您正在寻找这个巨大的东西
and you'd like to do that quickly.
并且您想快速地做到这一点。
Another application, s is what you type in Google.
另一个应用程序s是您在Google中键入的内容。
t is the entire web.
t是整个网络。
That's what Google does.
这就是Google所做的。
It searches for the string in the entire web.
它在整个网络中搜索字符串。
I'm not joking.
我不是在开玩笑。
OK?
好？
Fine.
精细。
So we'd like to do that.
因此，我们想这样做。
What's the obvious way to search for a substring
搜索子字符串的明显方法是什么
in a giant string?
大串？
Yeah?
是啊
AUDIENCE: Check each substring of that length.
听众：检查该长度的每个子串。
PROFESSOR: Just check each substring of the right length.
教授：只需检查每个正确长度的子串即可。
So it's got to be the length of s.
所以必须是s的长度。
And there's only a linear number of them, so check each one.
而且它们只有一个线性数，因此请检查每个。
Let's analyze that.
让我们来分析一下。
So a simple algorithm-- actually,
所以一个简单的算法-实际上，
just for fun, I have pseudocode for it.
只是为了好玩，我有伪代码。
I have Python code for it.
我有Python代码。
Even more cool.
更酷。
OK.
好。
I don't know if you know all these Python features,
我不知道您是否了解所有这些Python功能，
but you should.
但是你应该。
They're super cool.
他们超酷。
This is string splicing.
这是字符串拼接。
So we're looking in t-- let me draw the picture.
因此，我们正在寻找-让我来画画。
Here we have s, here we have t.
这里有s，这里有t。
Think of it as a big string.
认为它是一个很大的字符串。
We'd like to compare s like that,
我们想比较s
and then we'd like to compare s shifted over one to see
然后我们想比较s移一个
whether all of the characters match there.
是否所有字符都在那里匹配。
And then shifted over one more, and so on.
然后再移一个，依此类推。
And so we're looking at a substring of t from position
所以我们从位置看t的子串
i the position i plus the length of s,
我的位置我加上s的长度，
not including the last one.
不包括最后一个。
So that's of length exactly, length of s.
这就是长度，即s的长度。
This is s.
这是s。
This is t.
这是t。
And so each of these looks like that pattern.
因此，每个看起来都像那个模式。
We compare s to t.
我们将s与t进行比较。
What this comparison operation does
此比较操作的作用
in Python is it checks the first characters,
在Python中，它检查第一个字符，
see if they're equal.
看看他们是否相等。
If they are, keep going until they find a mismatch.
如果是这样，请继续进行下去，直到发现不匹配为止。
If there's no mismatch, then you return true.
如果没有不匹配，则返回true。
Otherwise, you return false.
否则，您返回false。
And then we do this roughly length of t times
然后我们大约进行了t次
because that's how many shifts there are, except at the end
因为那是多少班，除了最后
we run out of room.
我们用完了。
We don't care if we shift beyond the right
我们不在乎是否超越正确的方向
because that's clearly not going to match.
因为那显然不会匹配。
And so it's actually length of t minus like of s.
因此，它实际上是t减去s之类的长度。
That's the number of iterations.
那就是迭代次数。
Hopefully I got all the index arithmetic right.
希望我所有的索引算术都正确。
And there's no plus ones or minus ones.
而且没有加号或减号。
I think this is correct.
我认为这是正确的。
We want to know whether any of these match.
我们想知道是否这些匹配。
If so, the answer is yes, s occurs as a substring of t.
如果是，则答案为是，s作为t的子字符串出现。
Of course, in reality you want to know not just do any match,
当然，实际上，您不仅想知道做任何比赛，
but show them to me, things like that.
但是给他们看给我看
But you can change that.
但是你可以改变它。
Same amount of time.
时间相同。
So what's the running time of this algorithm?
那么该算法的运行时间是多少？
So my relevant things are the length of s
所以我相关的是s的长度
and the length of t.
和t的长度
What's the running time?
几点钟了？
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE]
观众：[听不清]
PROFESSOR: Sorry?
教授：对不起？
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE]
观众：[听不清]
PROFESSOR: T by-- t multiplied by s, yeah.
教授：T by-- t乘以s，是的。
Exactly.
究竟。
Technically, it's length of s times length of t minus s.
从技术上讲，它是s的长度乘以t的长度减去s的长度。
But typically, this is just s times t.
但是通常，这只是s倍。
And it's always at most s times t,
而且总是最多s倍，
and it's usually the same thing because s is usually smaller--
而且通常是同一回事，因为s通常较小-
at least a constant factor than t.
至少比t恒定。
This is kind of slow.
这有点慢。
If you're searching for a big string, it's not so great.
如果您要搜索的是大字符串，那不是很好。
I mean, certainly you need s plus t.
我的意思是，当然您需要s加t。
You've got to look at the strings.
您必须查看字符串。
But s times t is kind of-- it could be quadratic,
但是s有时是t的二次方，
if you're searching for a really long string in another string.
如果要在另一个字符串中搜索很长的字符串。
So what we'd like to do today is use
所以我们今天要做的就是使用
hashing to get this down to linear time.
哈希以将其降至线性时间。
So, ideas?
那么，想法？
How could we do that?
我们该怎么做？
Using hashing.
使用哈希。
Subtle hint.
微妙的提示。
Yeah?
是啊
AUDIENCE: If we take something into account [INAUDIBLE].
听众：如果我们考虑到某些问题[听不清]。
PROFESSOR: OK, so you want to decompose your string
教授：好的，所以您想分解字符串
into words and use the fact that there
变成文字并使用事实
are fewer words than characters.
单词少于字符。
You could probably get something out of that,
您可能会从中得到一些好处，
and old search engines used to do that.
和旧的搜索引擎曾经这样做。
But it's not necessary, turns out.
事实证明，这不是必须的。
And it will also depend on what your average word length is.
而且，这还取决于您的平均单词长度。
We are, in the end, today, we're not going to analyze it fully,
最后，今天，我们将不进行全面分析，
but we are going to get an algorithm that
但是我们要得到一个算法
runs in this time guaranteed.
在这段时间内运行。
In expectation because of a randomized-- yeah?
因为随机而期望-是吗？
AUDIENCE: If we were to hash [INAUDIBLE] size s, that would
观众：如果我们要对[音频不清晰] size进行哈希处理，
[INAUDIBLE] and then we would check the hash [INAUDIBLE].
[音频不清晰]，然后我们将检查哈希值[音频不清晰]。
PROFESSOR: Good.
教授：很好。
So the idea is to-- what we're looking
所以想法是-我们正在寻找
at is a rolling window of t always of size s.
at是总大小为s的t的滚动窗口。
And at each time we want to know, is it the same as s?
并且每次我们想知道的时候，它与s相同吗？
Now, if somehow-- it's expensive to check
现在，如果不知何故-检查起来很昂贵
whether a string is equal to a string.
字符串是否等于字符串。
There's no way getting around that.
没有办法解决这个问题。
Well, there are ways, but there isn't a way for just
好吧，有办法，但是没有办法
given two strings.
给出两个字符串。
But if somehow instead of checking the strings we
但是如果以某种方式而不是检查字符串，我们
could check a hash function of the strings,
可以检查字符串的哈希函数，
because strings are big, potentially.
因为字符串可能很大。
We don't know how big s is.
我们不知道s有多大。
And so the universe of strings of length s
因此，长度为s的弦的宇宙
is potentially very big.
可能很大。
It's expensive to compare things.
比较事物是昂贵的。
If we could just hash it down to some reasonable size,
如果我们可以将其哈希到合理的大小，
to something that fits in a word,
恰如其分地
then we can compare whether those two words are equal,
然后我们可以比较这两个词是否相等，
whether those two hash values are equal,
那两个哈希值是否相等，
whether there's a collision in the table.
桌子上是否有碰撞。
That would somehow-- that would make things go faster.
那将以某种方式使事情进展得更快。
We could do that in constant time per operation.
我们可以在每次操作的固定时间内执行此操作。
How could we do that?
我们该怎么做？
That's the tricky part, but that is exactly the right idea.
那是棘手的部分，但这是正确的想法。
So-- make some space.
所以-腾出一些空间。
I think I'm going to do things a little out of order
我想我会做些混乱的事情
from what I have in my notes, and tell you
从我的笔记中告诉你
about something called rolling hashes.
关于所谓的滚动哈希。
And then we'll see how they're used.
然后，我们将了解它们的用法。
So shelve that idea.
所以搁置这个想法。
We're going to come back to it.
我们将回到它。
We need a data structure to help us do this.
我们需要一个数据结构来帮助我们做到这一点。
Because if we just compute the hash function of this thing,
因为如果我们仅计算该事物的哈希函数，
compare it to the hash function of this thing,
比较它与这个东西的哈希函数，
and then compute the hash function of the shifted value
然后计算移位值的哈希函数
of t and compare it, we don't have
并比较它，我们没有
to recompute the hash of s.
重新计算s的哈希值。
That's going to be free once you do it once.
一旦执行一次，该操作将是免费的。
But computing the hash function of this
但是计算这个的哈希函数
and then the hash function of this
然后这个的哈希函数
and the hash function of this, usually
和它的哈希函数，通常
to compute each of those hash function
计算每个哈希函数
would take length of s time.
将花费s的时间。
And so we're not saving any time.
因此，我们不会节省任何时间。
Somehow, if we have the hash function of this,
不知何故，如果我们具有此哈希函数，
the first substring of length s, we'd
长度s的第一个子串，
like to very quickly compute the hash function
喜欢非常快速地计算哈希函数
of the next substring in constant time.
下一个子字符串在恒定时间内的时间。
Yeah?
是啊
AUDIENCE: You already have, like, s minus 1
听众：您已经有s减1
of the characters of the--
-
PROFESSOR: Yeah.
教授：是的。
If you look at this portion of s and this portion of s,
如果您查看的这部分和的这部分，
they share s minus 1 of the characters.
他们共享s减去-1个字符。
Just one character different.
只是一个字符不同。
First one gets deleted, last character gets added.
第一个被删除，最后一个字符被添加。
So here's what we want.
这就是我们想要的。
Given a hash value-- maybe I should call this r.
给定一个哈希值-也许我应该将其称为r。
It's not the hash function.
这不是哈希函数。
Give it a rolling hash value.
给它一个滚动哈希值。
You might say, I'd like to be able to append a character.
您可能会说，我希望能够附加一个字符。
I should say, r maintains a string.
我应该说，r保持字符串。
There's some string, let's call it x.
有一些字符串，我们称它为x。
And what r.append of c does is add
C的r.append所做的是添加
character c to the end of x.
字符c到x的末尾。
And then we also want an operation
然后我们还想要一个手术
which is-- you might call it pop left in Python.
这是-您可能会称其为Python左弹出。
I'm going to call it skip.
我将其称为“跳过”。
Shorter.
短一点
Delete the first character of x.
删除x的第一个字符。
And assuming it's c.
并假设它是c。
So we can do this because over here,
所以我们可以这样做，因为在这里，
what we want to do is add this character, which
我们想要做的就是添加这个字符，
is like t of length of s.
就像长度为s的t一样。
And we want to delete this character
我们要删除这个字符
from the front, which is t of 0.
从前面开始，即t为0。
Then we will get the next strength.
然后，我们将获得下一个优势。
And at all times, r-- what's the point of this r?
而且在任何时候，r-这个r的意义是什么？
You can say r-- let's say open paren, close
你可以说r-假设打开括号，关闭
paren-- this will give you a hash value
括号-这将为您提供哈希值
of the current strength.
当前强度。
So this is basically h of x for some hash function
所以对于一些哈希函数，这基本上是x的h
h, some reasonable hash function.
h，一些合理的哈希函数。
If we could do this and we could do
如果我们能做到，我们就能做到
each of these operations in constant time,
这些操作都是在恒定的时间进行的，
then we can do string matching.
然后我们可以进行字符串匹配。
Let me tell you how.
让我告诉你如何。
This is called the Karp-Rabin string matching algorithm.
这称为Karp-Rabin字符串匹配算法。
And if it's not clear exactly what's allowed here,
如果不清楚在这里允许什么，
you'll see it as we use it.
使用过程中，您会看到它。
First thing I'd like to do is compute the hash function of s.
我想做的第一件事是计算s的哈希函数。
I only need to do that once, so I'll do it.
我只需要做一次，所以我会做。
In this data structure, the only thing you're allowed to do
在此数据结构中，您唯一要做的就是
is add characters.
是添加字符。
Initially you have an empty string.
最初，您有一个空字符串。
And so for each character in s I'll just append it,
因此，对于s中的每个字符，我都将其追加，
and now rs gives me a hash value of s.
现在rs给我一个s的哈希值。
OK?
好？
Now, I'd like to get started and compute
现在，我想开始计算
the hash function of the first s characters of t.
t的前s个字符的哈希函数。
So this would be t up to length of s.
因此，这将达到s的长度。
And I'm going to call this thing rt, that's
我将其称为rt，那就是
my rolling hash for t.
我的滚动哈希值。
And append those characters.
并附加这些字符。
So now rs is a rolling hash of s.
因此，现在rs是s的滚动哈希。
rt is a rolling hash of the first s characters in t.
rt是t中前s个字符的滚动哈希。
So I should check whether they're equal.
所以我应该检查它们是否相等。
If they're not, shift over by one.
如果不是，请向前移动一个。
Add one character at the end, delete character
最后添加一个字符，删除字符
from the beginning.
从一开始就。
I'm going to have to do this many times.
我将不得不做多次。
So I guess technically, I need to check
所以我想从技术上来说，我需要检查
whether these are equal first.
这些是否首先相等。
If they're equal, then we'll talk about it in a moment.
如果它们相等，那么我们稍后再讨论。
The main thing I need to do is this
我要做的主要是
for loop, which checks all of the other.
for循环，用于检查所有其他循环。
And all I need to do is throw away the first letter, which
我要做的就是丢掉第一个字母
I know is t of i minus length of s.
我知道我的t减去s的长度。
And add the next letter, which is going to be t of i.
并添加下一个字母，即i的t。
And then after I do that, I don't change hs
然后我做完之后，我不会改变hs
because that's fixed.
因为那是固定的。
That's just-- or, sorry, I switched from h
就是-抱歉，我从h换了
to-- in my notes I have h.
要-在我的笔记中我有h。
I've been switching to r, so all those h's are r's.
我一直在切换到r，所以所有的h都是r。
Sorry about that.
对于那个很抱歉。
So then if rs equals rt, then potentially that substring of t
因此，如果rs等于rt，则可能是t的子字符串
matches s.
符合s。
But it's potentially because we're hashing.
但这可能是因为我们正在哈希。
Things are only true in expectation.
事情只有在期望中是真实的。
There's some probability of failure.
有失败的可能性。
Just because the hash function of two strings comes out equal
仅仅因为两个字符串的哈希函数相等
doesn't mean the strings themselves are equal,
并不意味着弦线本身相等，
because there are collisions.
因为有碰撞
Even distinct strings may map to the same slot in the table.
甚至不同的字符串也可能映射到表中的同一插槽。
So what we do in this situation is check
所以我们在这种情况下要做的就是检查
whether s equals t-- I did it slightly less conveniently
s是否等于t--我不太方便
than before-- it's like i minus length of s plus 1 to i plus 1.
比以前少了-就像我减去s的长度加1到i加1。
Oh well.
那好吧。
It wasn't very beautiful but it works.
它不是很漂亮，但是可以用。
So in this case, I'm going to check it character
所以在这种情况下，我将检查字符
by character.
按字符。
OK?
好？
If they're equal, then we found a match.
如果它们相等，那么我们找到了一个匹配项。
So it's kind of OK that I spent all this time to check them.
所以我花所有的时间检查它们是可以的。
In particular, if I'm just looking for the first match--
特别是如果我只是在寻找第一场比赛，
like you're searching through a text document,
就像您在搜索文本文档一样，
you just care about the first match-- then you're done.
您只需要关心第一个比赛就可以了。
So yeah, I spent order s time to do this,
是的，我花了很多时间来做这个，
but if they're equal it's sort of worth that effort.
但是如果它们相等，那值得付出努力。
I found the match.
我找到了比赛。
If they're not equal, we basically
如果它们不相等，我们基本上
hope or we will engineer it so that this
希望或我们将其设计成这样
happens with probability at most 1/s.
发生的可能性最高为1 / s。
If we can do that, then the expected time here is constant.
如果我们能够做到这一点，那么这里的预期时间就是恒定的。
So that would be good because then, if skip and append
这样会很好，因为如果跳过并追加
take constant time and this sort of double checking
花费固定的时间，进行这种双重检查
only takes constant expected time-- except when we find
只需要恒定的预期时间-除非我们发现
matches and then we're OK with it--
匹配，然后我们就可以了-
then this overall thing will take linear time.
那么整个过程将花费线性时间。
In fact, the proper thing would be this is you pay s plus t,
实际上，正确的做法是您支付s加t，
then you also pay-- for each match that you want to report,
那么您还需要为要报告的每场比赛付费，
you pay length of s.
您支付s的长度。
I'm not sure whether you can get rid of that term.
我不确定您是否可以摆脱这个名词。
But in particular, if you just care about one match,
但特别是如果您只关心一场比赛，
this is linear time.
这是线性时间。
It's pretty cool.
它太酷了。
There's one remaining question, which
还有一个问题，
is how do you build this data structure?
您如何建立这种数据结构？
Is the algorithm clear though?
虽然算法清楚吗？
I mean, I wrote it out in gory detail
我的意思是我详细地写了出来
so you can really see what's happening,
这样您才能真正看到正在发生的事情，
also because you need to do it in your problem set
也因为您需要在问题集中进行
so I give you as much code to work from as possible.
所以我给你尽可能多的代码来工作。
Question?
题？
AUDIENCE: What is rs?
听众：什么是rs？
PROFESSOR: rs is going to represent a hash value of s.
教授：rs将代表s的哈希值。
You could just say h of s.
您可以说s的h。
But what I like to show is that all you need
但我想证明的是，您所需要的
are these operations.
这些操作。
And so given a data structure that
所以给定一个数据结构
will compute a hash function, given the append operation,
给定追加操作，将计算哈希函数，
what I did up here was just append every letter of s
我在这里所做的只是附加s的每个字母
into this thing, and then rs open paren,
进入这个东西，然后打开paren，
close paren gives me the hash function of s.
close paren给了我s的哈希函数。
AUDIENCE: You said you can do r.append over here,
听众：您说您可以在这里追加。
but then you said rs--
但后来你说
PROFESSOR: Yeah.
教授：是的。
So there are two rolling hashes.
因此，有两个滚动哈希。
One's called rs and one's called rt.
一个人叫rs，一个人叫rt。
This was an ADT and I didn't say it at the beginning-- line
这是ADT，开始时我没有说过
one I say rs equals a new rolling hash. rt equals
我说rs等于一个新的滚动哈希。 rt等于
a new rolling hash.
一个新的滚动哈希。
Sorry, I should bind my variables.
抱歉，我应该绑定变量。
So I'm using two of them because I
所以我用了两个，因为我
want to compare their values, like this.
想要像这样比较他们的价值。
Other questions?
还有其他问题吗？
It's actually a pretty big idea.
这实际上是一个很大的主意。
This is an algorithm from the '90s, so it's fairly recent.
这是90年代的算法，所以它是最近的。
And it's one of the first examples
这是第一个例子
of really using randomization in a super cool way, other
真的以超酷的方式使用随机化
than just hashing as a data structure.
不仅仅是将哈希作为数据结构。
All right.
好吧。
So the remaining thing to do is figure out
所以剩下要做的就是弄清楚
how to build this ADT.
如何构建此ADT。
What's the data structure that implements
什么是实现的数据结构
this, spending constant time for each of these operations.
为此，您需要为每个操作花费固定的时间。
Now, to tell you the truth, doing
现在，说实话，
it depends on which hashing method you use, which hash
这取决于您使用哪种哈希方法，哪种哈希
function you want to use.
您要使用的功能。
I just erased the multiplication method
我只是删除了乘法方法
because it's a pain to use the multiplication method.
因为使用乘法方法很痛苦。
Though I'll bet you could use it, actually.
尽管我敢打赌，实际上您可以使用它。
That's an exercise for you think about.
这是您要考虑的练习。
I'm going to use the division method
我将使用除法
because it's the simplest hash function.
因为它是最简单的哈希函数。
And it turns out, in this setting it does work.
事实证明，在这种设置下它确实可以工作。
We're not going to prove that this is true.
我们不会证明这是真的。
This is going to be true in expectation.
期望这将是正确的。
Expected time.
预计时间。
But Karp and Rabin proved that this running time
但是Karp和Rabin证明了这段跑步时间
holds, even if you just use a simple hash
成立，即使您只是使用简单的哈希
function of the division method where
除法功能在哪里
m is chosen to be a random prime.
m被选择为随机素数。
Let's say about is big as-- let's say at least as
比方说大-比方说至少
big as length of s.
与s的长度一样大。
The bigger you make it, the higher probability this
你做的越大，这的可能性就越大
is going to be true.
将会是真的。
But length of s will give you this on average.
但是s的长度平均会给你这个。
So we're not going to talk about in this class
因此，我们将不在本课中讨论
how to find a random prime, but the algorithm
如何找到随机素数，但算法
is choose a random number of about the right size
选择大小合适的随机数
and check whether it's prime.
并检查它是否是素数。
If it's not, do it again.
如果不是，请再次执行。
And by the prime number theorem, after log end trials
通过对数结束试验后的素数定理
you will find a prime.
你会发现一个素数。
And we're not going to talk about how
而且我们不会谈论如何
to check whether a number's prime, but it can be done.
检查数字是否为质数，但是可以做到。
All right.
好吧。
So we're basically done.
至此我们基本完成。
The point is to look at-- if you look at an append operation
关键是要看-如果您查看追加操作
and you think about how this hash function changes
然后考虑一下哈希函数如何变化
when you add a single character.
当您添加单个字符时。
Oh, I should tell you.
哦，我应该告诉你。
We're going to treat the string x as a multi digit number.
我们将把字符串x视为多位数。
This is the sort of prehash function.
这是一种预哈希函数。
And the base is the size of your alphabet.
基数是字母的大小。
So if you're using Ascii, it's 256.
因此，如果您使用的是Ascii，则为256。
If you're using some unique code, it might be larger.
如果您使用一些独特的代码，则可能更大。
But whatever the size of your characters in your string,
但是，不管字符串中字符的大小如何，
then when I add a character, this is like taking my number,
那么当我添加一个字符时，就像拿我的号码，
shifting it over by one, and then adding a new value.
将其移动一个，然后添加一个新值。
So how do I shift over by one?
那我该如何换一个呢？
I multiply by a.
我乘以
So if I have some value, some current hash value u,
因此，如果我有一些值，一些当前的哈希值u，
it changes to u times a-- or sorry,
它变为u倍-或对不起，
this is the number represented by the string.
这是由字符串表示的数字。
I multiply by a and then I add on the character.
我乘以a，然后加上字符。
Or, in Python you'd write ord of the character.
或者，在Python中，您要编写字符的ord。
That's the number associated with that character.
这是与该字符关联的数字。
That gives me the new string.
这给了我新的字符串。
Very easy.
很容易。
If I want to do is skip, it's slightly more annoying.
如果我想跳过，那会有点烦。
But skip means just annihilate this value.
但是跳过意味着只会消灭这个价值。
And so it's like u goes to u minus the character times a
就像你去u减去字符乘以a
to the power size of u minus 1.
到u的幂大小减去1。
I have to shift this character over to that position
我必须把这个角色移到那个位置
and then annihilated it with a minus sign.
然后用减号消灭它。
You could also do x or.
您也可以执行x或。
And when I do this, I just think about how
当我这样做时，我只是在想
the hash function is changing.
哈希函数正在更改。
Everything is just modulo m.
一切都只是模m。
So if I have some hash value here, r,
因此，如果我在这里有一些哈希值，r，
I take r times a plus ord of c and I just
我取r乘以c的正序，而我只是
do that computation modulo m, and I'll
进行模m运算，我将
get the new hash value.
获取新的哈希值。
Do the same thing down here, I'll get the new hash value.
在这里做同样的事情，我将获得新的哈希值。
So what r stores is the current hash value.
所以r存储的是当前哈希值。
And it stores a to the power length of u or length
并存储a到u的幂长度或length
of x, whatever you want to call it.
x，无论您想调用它什么。
I guess that would be a little better.
我想那会好一点。
And then it can do these in constant a number
然后它可以不断地做这些
of operations.
操作。
Just compute everything modulo m,
只需计算所有模m
one multiplication, one addition.
一乘一加。
You can do append and skip, and then you
您可以添加和跳过，然后
have the hash value instantly.
立即具有哈希值。
It's just stored.
它刚刚存储。
And then you can make all this work.
然后您就可以完成所有这些工作。